Divijesh Varma

AWS Solutions Architect

O Hyderabad & +918790071455 O divijesh@tuta.io

Summary

B. Tech Software Professional having 2 years of experience in AWS Cloud and 3 years of experience in Linux Administration. Where my role mainly involved in establishing AWS infrastructure. Managing and monitoring most of the activities and servers running on AWS cloud, Server level work on linux OS.

Experience

Future Nine Information Technologies Pvt Ltd

January 2022 - May 2024

Hyderabad

AWS Solutions Architect

- https://future9it.com/
 - Created and maintained IAM users, groups, roles, and policies to ensure secure and compliant access control. Implemented Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) for enhanced security of AWS accounts.
- Managed EC2 instances, configured Elastic Block Store (EBS) volumes, created and utilized Amazon Machine Images (AMIs), and implemented Elastic File System (EFS) for scalable, reliable storage.
- Configured and maintained Elastic Load Balancers (ELB) to distribute incoming traffic and enhance application availability. Designed and managed Auto Scaling Groups (ASG) to automatically adjust capacity based on demand, ensuring optimal performance and cost-efficiency.
- Managed AWS RDS instances for optimal database performance, availability, and security. Configured Route 53 DNS services with advanced routing policies to ensure reliable, scalable, and efficient traffic management.
- Configured and maintained Amazon S3 buckets for secure, scalable storage solutions. Implemented CloudFront distributions to deliver content globally with low latency and high transfer speeds, ensuring optimal user experience and performance.
- Implemented Amazon CloudWatch for comprehensive monitoring, logging, and alerting to ensure system performance and reliability. Designed and maintained Virtual Private Clouds (VPC) to provide secure, scalable network infrastructure, ensuring isolation and efficient resource allocation.
- Deployed and hosted a highly available WordPress application using Amazon EC2, RDS, Route 53, and VPC.

Locuz Enterprise Solutions

March 2020 - September 2020

Technology Associate

Hyderabad

- https://www.locuz.com/
- Experience with Linux user and group management, and granting other users superuser access as needed.
- Experience in Logical volume management (LVM), including creating and extending the size of logical volumes.
- Proficient in command-line storage management, including creating and managing storage devices, partitions, file systems, and swap spaces.
- Monitored and managed Linux processes to ensure system performance and stability, troubleshoot system issues, and optimize resource utilization.
- Experience with Linux service management, including the ability to control system daemons using systemctl. Configured and secured SSH on Linux systems by setting up key-based authentication

and customizing OpenSSH service configuration to improve security.

Way2online

July 2017 - October 2019

Process Associate

Hyderabad

- https://way2online.com/
 - Manage the boot process to control services offered and to troubleshoot and repair problems.
 - Experience in software Package management using RPM, YUM.
- Experienced in setting ACLs to handle complex access permissions and control file access.
- Archived and transferred files between systems securely by using tools such as SCP, rsync.
- Processes administration and Management like monitoring, start/stop/kill various processes.
- configuration files to control network settings. Archived and transferred files between systems securely by using tools such as SCP,

Configured and maintained networking on Linux systems by using nmcli and editing

Rsync.

•	Proficient in utilizing the NFS protocol to access network-attached storage, with
	expertise in automounting procedures for efficient storage access.

Education

Gopal Reddy College of Engineering and Technology

2010-2014

Electronics & Communication Engineering

B.Tech

Skills	AWS	Linux	Docker
	Kubernetes	Git	

Certifications

Red Hat Certified Engineer

April 2017

Red Hat

Red Hat Certified System Administrator Red Hat

March 2017

Languages

English

Telugu